<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Jekyll Bootstrap</title>
 <link href="http://username.github.io/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://username.github.io"/>
 <updated>2013-12-03T18:03:20-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://username.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Ulysses Zheng</name>
   <email>ulysses147@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello World</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.io/personal/2013/12/01/hello-world"/>
   <updated>2013-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.io/personal/2013/12/01/hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&#39;hello_everybody&#39;&gt;Hello everybody,&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website + blog is the result of about three weeks work, working when I don&amp;#8217;t have school work. I did not know any html/css/js before I did this, so it was an amazing learning experience. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#39;1_codecademy&#39;&gt;1. Codecademy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began by going through the &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.codecademy.com/&#39;&gt;codecademy&lt;/a&gt; tutorials to get a brief idea of html/css/js. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#39;2_twitterbootstrap&#39;&gt;2. Twitter-Bootstrap&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, I looked into the &lt;a href=&#39;http://getbootstrap.com/&#39;&gt;Twitter-Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; and stumbled upon this &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.realpython.com/blog/design/getting-started-with-bootstrap-3/#.Up1AhWSxN4F&#39;&gt;theme&lt;/a&gt; which I liked. So I took that and modified it to display my projects. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#39;3_google_app_engine&#39;&gt;3. Google App Engine&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had a prototype working, I looked for a website host. Although GAE is not exactly a web hosting platform, it does host static pages quite nicely. I also chose GAE, because I used it before for previous computing projects and it is free! &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#39;4_contact&#39;&gt;4. Contact&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I wanted a contact system of some sort, and found &lt;a href=&#39;http://myprogrammingblog.com/2013/08/27/how-to-make-a-contact-form-with-bootstrap-3-jqueryphphtml5jqbootstrapvalidation/&#39;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. Since I was using Google App Engine to host my website, and GAE has restrictions on sending email, I had to modify it. In the end I wrote a component in Python to send the email. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#39;5_the_blog&#39;&gt;5. The Blog&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to add a blog of some sort and I found &lt;a href=&#39;http://jekyllbootstrap.com/&#39;&gt;JekyllBootstrap&lt;/a&gt;. I thought about hosting my site on Github Pages instead, but that would mean I have to give up on the Contacts page, because Github Pages doesn&amp;#8217;t support php. Even if it did support php, I would also have to rewrite the contacts code as it only works for GAE. In the end, I stuck with JekyllBootstrap. I studied their examples and then added my website theme to it. The theme can be found &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/ulyssesz/narrow&#39;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this concludes a brief summary of the process I took, from having no experience in web development to creating this website.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>